# Vibha Suneel Navale

Bengaluru, India
(+91) 81055 00204

vibha.navale11@gmail.com

https://vibha-navale.netlify.app/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vibha-navale/

https://github.com/VibhaSNavale

#### **SUMMARY**

Passionate Software Engineer with 1+ years of experience in developing scalable applications using a wide range of frontend and back-end tools such as React, CSS, and Node.js; along with necessary AWS infrastructural, Git, and product testing skills.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Engineer**

### **Cimpress**

August 2021 - Present

- I work on several products (front- and back-end) that help mass manufacturing plants aggregate items and keep track of the orders' state until they are delivered to the customers.
- To enrich the user experience, I helped develop APIs and features that allow users to interact efficiently with the software as they add items to or fetch items from the bins.
- Played a major role in the development of a UI that allows users to seamlessly create bins and monitor their usage while performing important actions and assigning items to them.
- I proactively monitor services provided to users while ensuring real-time issues are resolved as quickly as possible.

# Android Developer Intern NS Jain Constructions

June 2020 - July 2020

I performed a key role in the development process of an android application for NS Jain Constructions. I worked on a construction material shopping app, particularly for sand. The app was made in Android Studio in Java and uses Firebase. It is available on Google Play Store by the name 'NS SAND MARKET'.

### **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

RNS Institute of Technology, Bengaluru – Information Science and Engineering (B.E. - 9.08 CGPA) (2017 - 2021)

**Vidya Jyothi PU College** – 12th grade (Computer Sc.) (2016 - 2017)

R.L. Jalappa Central School – 10th grade (2014-2015)

#### SKILLS

TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Angular, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Java, C++, PostgreSQL, REST API, Jest, Mocha, AWS, Git, Android App Development, Visual Studio Code, Postman, DBeaver

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Best outgoing student' recognition in academics (2021)
- Best major project award in Al/ML track in an interdepartment competition, PROP (Project Open-house Panorama). This project was also VTU sponsored for financial assistance (2021)
- Secured one of the top 3 positions in a departmentlevel technical debugging contest (2019)
- Completed an MTA certification (Introduction to Programming using JavaScript) and scored 85/100 (2019)
- 'Best Outgoing Student' award in 10th grade (2015)

# **PROJECTS**

 Design and Implementation of Eye Pupil Movement-based PIN Authentication System — Major project (Aug 2020 - Jul 2021)

- Breast Cancer Prediction Internship project (Nov 2020 - Jan 2021)
- E-library website Web Technology mini project (Nov 2020 Jan 2021)
- Food order management system File Structures mini project (May 2020)
- E-Auction System DBMS mini project (Nov 2019 Dec 2019)
- Face recognition system using OpenCV Personal project (Jul 2019 - Aug 2019)

# **PUBLICATIONS**

"Blink Detection Based PIN Verification", International Journal of Science & Engineering Development Research (www.ijrti.org), ISSN:2455-2631, Vol.7, Issue 10, page no.366 - 372, October-2022

### **LANGUAGES**

English, Hindi, Kannada, Marathi